Good morning, Charlie.
Charlie?
Good, I don't have to give him
mouth-to-mouth.
- Morning.
Morning.
- He's sleeping?
- Sure, let's call it sleep.
Uncle Charlie, I'm gonna have a bowl
of Maple Loops, you want one?
Are you sure he's okay?
I never said he was okay.
Freaky.
You really shouldn't see him
like this, Jake.
There, now you can
enjoy your breakfast.
- What's wrong with him?
- Oh, he's getting old, kiddo.
I wish you could've seen him
in his prime.
He was like Babe Ruth.
He played baseball?
No, he was a drunken whoremonger.
But there was none better.
Oh, God, look what the cat dragged in.
He didn't just drag it.
He ate it, pooped it out
and then covered it with sand.
You know what would be funny?
To paint a big mustache on him.
That would be hilarious, but no.
Charlie?
Yeah?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
What time did you get home?
I'm home?
You are.
Oh, God, I'm blind.
It's a miracle.
Okay, see you tomorrow.
Good night, Berta.
Hey.
Look who's finally up.
How'd you sleep?
Okay, I guess.
Good, I'm glad.
- Oh. Tater Tots.
- Help yourself.
- Jake, I said no.
- I didn't do it.
He didn't.
What are you staring at?
Nothing, señor.
So how are you feeling?
That depends. What day is it?
Saturday.
Oh. Well, in that case, I feel great.
Why in that case?
If it was Thursday, I'd be a little worried.
I don't know,
you've been pushing it hard lately.
- What do you mean?
- You're not a kid anymore.
Oh, please.
I'm in the best shape of my life.
Oh, that doesn't belong inside of me.
It takes a lot to gross me out, but wow.
Get your stuff together.
I'll bring you back to your mom's.
Let me tell you something.
You're only as young
as the women you feel.
And lately, I've been feeling about 24.
- Twenty-four?
- Yup.
She doesn't think I'm old.
She thinks I'm cute and fun.
- And rich.
- Yeah, the rich helps.
I'm not that cute.
Okay, fine. I understand the allure,
the nectar of the young berry.
I know what happens
burning a candle at both ends.
How would you know that? Did you take a
candle-making class at the Learning Annex?
Hey, I have done my share
of walking on the wild side.
The wild side?
Okay, the rambunctious side.
There comes a time in a mars life when
he has to start accepting his limitations.
Yeah, well, my point is,
the day you start accepting limitations...
...is the day you start dying.
And I'm not dying, my friend,
I am living life to the fullest.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm gonna go throw up and take a nap.
That was fun.
- Yeah.
- How long until you're ready to go again?
You mean, tonight?
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
You're old.
Hey, hey, hey, I'm not old.
I'm just not a yogurt dispenser.
You're almost as old as my dad.
All right, listen, if you're looking to
go again, that's not the way to get there.
Aw. Did I hurt your feelings?
No, no, you didn't hurt my feelings.
It's just there are certain biological
factors you have to take into account...
Yeah, my dad takes viagra.
Good for him.
All I'm saying is, we could do something
else for a while and come back to this.
- Great. Let's go to a club.
- Now?
It's 11:00.
So we'll get there early.
Actually I was thinking
more along the lines...
...of making some toaster pizzas
and watching The Daily Show.
- Oh.
- What?
I'm bored.
If we're not gonna have sex, you know,
I wanna go out.
Okay, tell you what...
...why don't you go out and,
you know, boogie oogie oogie?
And when you come back,
wake me up and we'll have sex.
That's a lame idea, Charlie.
Okay, you can skip
the waking-me-up part.
- I'm just gonna go call some friends.
- No, no, no, wait.
Come here. Come here.
I think I'm ready to go again.
- Really?
- Really.
I got nothing. Let's go dancing.
Yeah, I'm coming with the guy
I told you about. The old guy.
I don't know. I think he's got
a little brother who's old too.
I'll ask him. Great, we'll see you there.
Think your brother would wanna come?
Alan? No, he's not the type.
He'd be miserable going to a club
at this hour.
Wait here. I'll go get him.
- Hey.
- Oh, you just missed it.
Jon Stewart made a very clever joke
about the budget deficit.
Swell.
Get dressed. We're going dancing.
Yeah, right. Toaster pizza?
No. Come on. Let's go.
- Are you serious?
- Yes.
But it's after 11 and I'm all tucked in.
- Too bad.
- I'm drinking Nighty-Night tea.
Come on. Robin wants to go dancing
and I'm gonna need a designated driver.
Hey, just because you're being a fool
trying to keep up with a 24-year-old girl...
...doesn't mean I have to join you.
- She has a 24-year-old friend.
Is it dressy-dressy or dressy-casual?
Just take it. Maybe it'll loosen you up.
I don't think so.
Recent studies indicate that Ecstasy
may well deplete your spinal fluid.
Yeah, so?
So? Young lady, I am a chiropractor.
Whoo.
You know what?
My date isn't working out.
Maybe you'd get somewhere
if you didn't talk to her like her father.
Well, somebody has to because her real
father has obviously dropped the ball.
Oh, wonderful, a smoker.
So I guess you're counting on stem-cell
research to replace your spine and lungs.
Alan, Alan, you're embarrassing me.
Oh, I'm embarrassing you?
Look at yourself.
You're standing in line in a dank alley
in the middle of the Urine District.
Hey, hey, hey,
this is the hippest club in town.
Oh, hip, schmip.
It's a toilet with a doorman.
Somebody lit a doobie.
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
That is definitely the ganja.
Oh, great,
now we're all gonna get busted.
Will you just relax
and let yourself have some fun?
Oh, this is fun for you?
Exhaust fumes and reefer smoke?
Let me tell you something.
I am not a kid.
I need plenty of rest, exercise
and a high-fiber diet and...
oh, perfect, I just stepped on a condom.
Go ahead. Have a good time.
- Hold it.
- We're with them.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, no, no. We are.
Truth be told, I don't see a long-term
relationship in the offing. You understand.
Don't touch the rope.
Sorry.
I didn't realize you were king of the rope.
Shut up, Alan.
You're not on the list,
you're not getting in.
- You let the girls in.
- Alan...
He let the girls in.
That's because pretty girls
dress up the place.
Watch how this works.
Listen, why don't you check your list
for Jackson?
Andrew Jackson.
Nope. Got Tito and La Toya.
Okay.
What if I change my name to...
...Ulysses S. Grant?
You could change your name
to Condoleezza Rice.
If you're not on the list and you're not
a celebrity, you're not getting in.
All right, look, I didn't wanna have
to play this card but I'm Charlie Harper.
I'm in the music business.
I wrote the Maple Loops jingle.
Granny's Big Fudge Nuggets?
- Oh, I love those cookies.
- Great.
- You got any on you?
- No.
Beat it.
Charlie, Charlie, let me handle this.
Sir...
...I am Matthew Broderick.
Who?
Bruno, they're with me.
Are you sure?
This is a good chance to cut them loose.
Guys, come on.
Matthew Broderick is a gifted actor
and the toast of Broadway.
Oh, for God's sake,
will you stop complaining?
Well, I'm sorry, but the music in that club
was so loud, my ears are still ringing.
You know what that sound is? That is
the sound of the hairs in my ear dying.
I am talking permanent hearing loss,
Charlie.
Those little hairs don't grow back.
Oh, wait. Let's see something.
C- sharp.
C- sharp is the sound
of encroaching deafness.
Listen to you. You're like an old man.
I can't listen to me. All I hear is:
Worst night of my life.
You're just ticked off
because you couldn't keep up.
I couldn't keep up?
I was out on the dance floor with the girls,
while you were sleeping in the booth.
I wasrt sleeping.
I was closing my eyes because
I couldn't bear to watch you do this:
I was voguing.
You were napping.
Nobody vogues anymore, Alan.
And guess what,
nobody does the robot anymore either.
Oh, yeah? Then why
did it catch on with the others?
It didn't catch on.
They were openly mocking you.
What do you want from me?
I went to the club.
I went to the after-hours club.
I went out to breakfast.
I held my date's hair while she vomited
pancakes in the parking lot.
If you werert whining
about wanting to go home...
...you'd be having sex with her
right now.
Oh, darn. What man doesn't dream
of kissing secondhand pancakes?
And I have to go to work.
You know what? You are a fuddy-duddy.
I'm...? I'm a fuddy-duddy?
Hey, if the orthopedic shoe fits, wear it.
They are not orthopedic.
They merely have a reinforced arch
for the active lifestyle.
And you were napping.
Okay, maybe I needed a little shuteye.
But that's only because
I had vigorous sex earlier.
Oh, let's face it.
We're both too old for the MTv lifestyle.
MTv? Did they just defrost you?
Okay. MTv, vH1,
whatever the kids are watching.
My point is,
I am comfortable acting my age...
...while you are in deep denial.
Hey, hey,
I am not in denial about anything.
I am a young, vibrant man
in the prime of my life. I'm...
What?
Young people have phlegm too.
Sure.
Anyway, as I was...
oh, God.
What's the matter?
My chest.
Are you okay?
I don't know.
- Hey, Alan?
- Yeah.
Do you think it's too late
to start jogging?
Damn it, what kind of hospital
is this? Where the hell are the doctors?
That's my brother in there.
If he dies, I'm homeless.
Uh, everything's fine.
Uh, they're just gonna run some tests.
Not to worry.
Easy for you to say.
Listen, Alan.
If I don't make it,
you need to know about my will.
Hey, I don't wanna hear that kind of talk.
You're gonna make it.
But go on. Finish what you were saying.
First of all,
I left the house to you and Jake.
Yes!
You're gonna make it.
Just so you know,
there's two mortgages on it...
...and the property taxes
are $50,000 a year.
Uh, 50,000?
Uh, excuse me.
Do you gotta flatline
to get a little help around here?
Do you gotta move to Canada
to get some decent medical care?
Uh, they'll be right here.
So 50 grand, huh?
Boy, I don't know
how I could afford that.
You know,
unless I came into some money.
You know, an ineritance or something.
There's no money, Alan.
None?
The whole thing's a house of cards.
Huh.
Okay, I did not wanna have to do this...
...but I am Matthew Broderick.
And that is my brother lying there.
I am so sorry, Mr. Broderick.
- I loved you in The Producers.
Thank you.
Okay, let's have a look-see, huh?
According to your tests, you just had
an acute attack of indigestion.
- It was gas?
- Yes. A big bubble.
About the size of a pomegranate.
What have you had to eat recently?
Nothing much.
He had Belgian waffles,
link sausages, two Red Bulls...
...a quart of Scotch
and the tongue of a 24-year-old actress.
He asked what I ate, Alan.
And I told him, Charlie.
Oh-ho, you're a dirty bird.
Well, the good news is that you are
a perfectly healthy 50-year-old man.
I'm only 40.
Tell that to your liver.
I would recommend you slow down a bit.
- I've been saying the same thing.
- And you.
Why no sequel to Ferris Bueller, huh?
I wait and I wait.
I'm sorry, I'll get on it.
Ah, give the people what they want.
So gas.
Good news, huh?
- A little embarrassing, but yeah.
- What are you embarrassed about?
I don't know.
The paramedics, the ambulance...
...the crying and the last-minute
negotiations with God.
Oh, right. Are you still planning
on teaching piano to orphans?
If any show up, sure.
All right. Well, will you at least accept
the fact that you have to slow down?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's weird, Alan.
It seems like just yesterday, I could...
I could party all night,
eat and drink anything I wanted to.
Now a couple of Red Bulls and a waffle...
...and I'm sitting in the emergency room
praying for a fart.
Now you know why I ordered
tomato juice and cottage cheese.
- I admit, you take good care of yourself.
- I try.
I guess that's why I keep you around.
Because I'm a good example?
No, you clod, spare parts.
What are we watching?
Antiques Roadshow.
This woman thinks she has
Martha Washingtors butter churn.
Huh.
Toaster pizza?
Thank you.
- So are you going out tonight?
- Ah, what's the point?
Look, Charlie,
I'm glad you're slowing down a bit...
...but you haven't been out of the house
in a week.
Ah, it's too depressing.
Wherever I go,
I'm the oldest guy in the room.
Even here.
Hey, what would you think
about getting a cat?
Okay, that's it. Put some clothes on.
We're going out.
It's 9:00.
I was gonna make some kettle corn.
Forget the corn. You're coming with me.
- Where are we going?
- You'll see.
Can you drive?
I don't like to drive at night.
What the hell is this place?
- The fountain of youth.
- What?
Follow me.
Ooh, look, young stuff.
Alan, you're a genius.
- May I ask you a personal question?
- Sure.
How old are you?
I just turned 40.
Ah! You're a baby.
Well, yeah.
Hey, I have a little riddle for you.
All right.
What has multiple orgasms and hums?
I give up.
Oh.
Come on, I'll show you.
Alan? Alan, I'm leaving.
And may God bless you.